understanding these types of drawings is
what allowed me to generate numbers like
these these or even these and that is
one of the keys to my success with my
set and forget strategy because it
allows me exactly to know when I should
buy or sell and in this very video I'm
going to explain to you each and all of
the most important Candlestick patterns
which ones they are how to understand
them and most importantly how to profit
the out of them how my students and
I do every single day for me there's two
type of Candlestick patterns that are
the most effective and that is
continuation and reversal patterns the
first one is the continuation patterns
which are the ones that show us that
it's going to pretty much do what it
says it's going to continue the trend of
the market so this means that the
continuation pattern will confirm that
price will follow the trend which is the
direction of the market and then the
second one is the reversal pattern which
literally shows us the complete opposite
of the continuation when the
continuation keeps with the trend the
reversal patterns show us when the price
is going to reverse to a different
direction these are the patterns that
are going to indicate IND to us that the
price is going to change the trend of
the market and for any newbies out there
trend is also known as the direction of
where the market is headed so if you
have a reversal pattern this means if
the market was bullish now the market is
going to shift bearish due to these
indication of these reversal patterns
and obviously vice versa if we are
bearish and then we have a reversal
pattern this is going to indicate to us
that the market is going to change Trend
there as well so let's take a deeper
look into this and let me explain in
much more detail the best Candlestick
patterns that I use every single day
along with my students to generate loads
of profits so my first and most
effective one is the engulfing
Candlestick so it's pretty
self-explanatory it engulfs the previous
one to2 candlesticks that's why it's
called an engulfing candlesticks because
it eats the last price action indicating
that price is going to continue or
reverse depends how you use it going to
explain a little bit more about this
later in the video this Candlestick
tells us that there is a lots of buyers
in the market so if we have a huge
bullish and golfing candlesticks that
means there's a lot of buyers if we have
a huge bearish engulfing candlesticks
that means we have a lot of Sellers and
this is all these buyers and sellers
operating in the market in real time
because you can see it reflect on the
acceleration and on the strength of the
actual price action which is the
Candlestick in my case I consider an
engulfing when it closes above and eats
the last two candlesticks this is the
strongest indication you can get and you
want to make sure you have this bullish
engulfing Candlestick at an air of
Interest rejection from an EMA and loads
of other Confluence that give you
confirmation that this Candlestick is
going to be valid and going to continue
heading in that direction but more about
this later in the video the second most
important Candlestick is the hammer or
also known as the shooting St it plays
both sides let me explain this is a
pattern that depending on the Zone where
price is it's going to show us something
completely different usually we
interpret the hammer Candlestick and the
shooting star as a reversal pattern but
they can also be continuation patterns
in some cases and the way you get these
hammers or these shooting stars is is by
when price comes into a Zone and has a
strong rejection and it creates this
Wick Wick is also known as a tail which
is basically a footprint of where the
market has been in those past minutes in
those past hours or whatever time frame
you are on in that specific Candlestick
so let's just suppose price comes into a
support level and then it rejects it and
it leaves a huge Wick or a tail that is
a footprint indicating that the price
did not like that zone and then it is
rejecting it so this can show you that
price is not going to continue heading
to the opposite direction of where that
footprint was left and for a simple
analogy of what the footprint is of the
market it's like if you step on a pho
and you walk through a dry floor you can
clearly see that somebody's been there
that's exactly what the wick is you can
see that price has clearly hit his own
but it's rejected it because it didn't
like it and the supply and demand Zone
were rejecting price from that point
next we have a double top or a double
bottom and these are actually very
simple to explain because it literally
means exactly what I'm saying it's a
double top and a double bottom formation
let me explain this is a reversal
pattern of once price gets to an area of
interest and then it rejects from it two
times but it's very specific so you get
a double top form when price reaches an
area of interest and then it rejects
from it and then once price comes back
into the area to then retest another
time and it rejects again this is when
you have a double top formation this is
usually formed at a resistance level and
for a double bottom information it's
exactly the same this is when price
heads down to the floor of the price it
rejects it and then it comes back and it
does it once again and then it rejects
it as well this is known as a double
bottom and a double top formation these
are beautiful reversal patterns that I
use all the time in the markets and they
generate me loads of profits and this is
a very simple and clean reversal pattern
that a lot of beginners use and then if
you use it the right way it can be very
beneficial to you next we have the most
powerful reversal pattern I believe and
it is the most overlooked in the market
and people think it's very complicated
but it's actually very easy to see and
once you see it it's almost like you
can't unsee it it's like where's Waldo
as soon as you see Waldo on the map you
can't unsee it it's the same thing with
this next pattern and it is called The
Head and Shoulders pattern once you see
it in the market it's like you can't
unsee it you're going to see it
everywhere and this reversal pattern is
called that because it's exactly what it
is it's a left it's a head and then a
right shoulder very simple and very very
effective this pattern is very powerful
especially when it occurs at a strong
area of Interest now keep in mind this
is only a reversal pattern so so if you
have a head and shoulders at a top of a
resistance level this is going to
indicate that the market is now going to
reverse to the downside if you have an
inverted Head and Shoulders at the
bottom of a trend this is going to
indicate to you that the market is now
going to reverse and start heading to
the upside here you can see many
examples of head and shoulders in the
markets playing out time and time and
time again this is one of the most
effective patterns but it requires a lot
of patience but as soon as you master
noticing these Head and Shoulders it's
going to be very very beneficial to to
you're trading next we have a dogee
Candlestick these tend to occur in very
specific zones in the market let me
explain so this is very similar to the
other ones but this one will form at
very strong areas of Interest or support
and resistance liquidity zones they're
all the same thing so this one's very
similar to the other ones but the
formation of a dogee at a strong area of
Interest a support and resistance is
much more effective and it is very very
powerful so a doe is when price creates
a very small body but then it leaves a
footprint that price Rejects to the
upside and price rejected to the
downside a DOI is also looked like a
plus sign this is indicating that there
is Major unision in the market and this
can be huge for reversal because if this
happens at a strong area of Interest
these are strong indications that there
will be a reversal in the market so a
dogee is formed when it has a footprint
to the downside and a footprint to the
upside with a very small body and in
this example right here you can see how
the dogee is very powerful when it used
at a level of support and resistance and
the more does you have the more
indication you have that it is going to
reverse and this pattern is usually
combined with our next one which is a
morning star or evening star Morning
Star is formed when it is going to go
bullish An Evening Star is formed when
it is going to go bearish when the dogee
and The Morning Star is combined it is
one of the most powerful entry signals
you can get in the market same thing for
the evening star in this case this is
when you get a large Candlestick to
reach a level of support Then followed
by a dogee Candlestick and then the next
one is a bullish engulfing this is known
as a Morning Star rejection this sets
for a major high probability trade that
is going to reverse or continuation
depending what you're looking to do in
the market in this example right here
you can see how price reached the level
of support it rejected the level of
support and resistance we had the red
Candlestick we had the dogee and then we
had the bullish engulfing where it then
continued the formation to the upside
this type of example you're going to see
time and time time again in the markets
I've been doing this now for 6 years and
I don't stop seeing this information
happening again and again and again and
these here are the most relevant and the
most common candlesticks out there but a
lot of people don't understand them
properly but this is how I interpret
them this is how I teach my students to
interpret it because it is very simple
and very effective and I use it on a
daily basis with my centria strategies
to generat me figures like these these
or even these and if you want to learn
more about my centa strategy and how it
generates new Traders anywhere from ,000
to $11,500 a week as a beginner setting
forget Trader just hit the link in the
description below I have a video for you
that explains absolutely everything from
0 to 100 and you can probably be one of
my students and one of my success
stories that I have where I have Traders
generating over six figures a month with
only one year of doing this and
generating anywhere from a th000 to
$1,500 a week in the first three months
of using the set and forget strategy so
I hope you guys found this video useful
thank you guys for watching the video
all the way to the end make sure to hit
that like subscribe button and I'll see
you guys in the next one